<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.miles.horizon</id>

  <name>Horizon</name>
  <summary>Multi-provider AI chat — Ollama, Claude, OpenAI, Gemini</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      Horizon is a Flutter chat client that talks to Ollama, Claude, OpenAI, and Gemini from a single app.
      Pick provider and model per conversation, switch mid-thread, and keep API keys in the OS keystore.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Four providers in one client: Ollama (local), Claude (Anthropic), OpenAI, Gemini (Google)</li>
      <li>Per-chat provider, model, system prompt, and inference options</li>
      <li>Primary + backup Ollama URL with automatic failover — keep your home-LAN server private and fall back to a VPN/Tailscale endpoint transparently</li>
      <li>API keys stored in the OS keystore via libsecret</li>
      <li>Image input on vision-capable models</li>
      <li>Smooth streaming output with typewriter buffering</li>
      <li>OLED-true-black dark theme</li>
      <li>Edit and regenerate any message in the conversation</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Horizon is a fork of Reins by Ibrahim Çetin. The original Ollama-focused client and Flutter scaffolding are his work; Horizon extends it into a multi-provider client with hardened networking and self-hosted-friendly features.
    </p>
  </description>

  <icon type="stock">com.miles.horizon</icon>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.miles.horizon.desktop</launchable>

  <developer id="dev.60milesperhour">
    <name>Miles Oldenburger</name>
  </developer>

  <categories>
    <category>Utility</category>
    <category>Network</category>
    <category>Chat</category>
    <category>Development</category>
  </categories>

  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>

  <supports>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>touch</control>
  </supports>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/60MilesPerHour/Horizon</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/60MilesPerHour/Horizon</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/60MilesPerHour/Horizon/issues</url>

  <releases>
    <release version="3.2.2" date="2026-05-19">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/60MilesPerHour/Horizon/releases/tag/v3.2.2</url>
      <description>
        <p>Linux release, scroll polish.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>First Linux release: .deb for Debian/Ubuntu/Mint/Pop and .tar.gz for other distros.</li>
          <li>Fixed a blank-screen flash between sending a prompt and the first streamed token.</li>
          <li>Fixed sticky touch scrolling on 120 Hz screens during long streams.</li>
          <li>Restored platform-native overscroll feel (Android stretch, iOS bounce).</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.2.1" date="2026-05-18">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/60MilesPerHour/Horizon/releases/tag/v3.2.1</url>
      <description>
        <p>Ollama context-size fix.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Stopped forcing num_ctx=2048 on every Ollama request, which was making the server unload and reload models that were already running at a different context size.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="3.2.0" date="2026-05-18">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/60MilesPerHour/Horizon/releases/tag/v3.2.0</url>
      <description>
        <p>Scroll engine rewrite, Gemini provider, backup Ollama URL.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Rewrote the chat scroll engine — long responses no longer feel like a slideshow during or after generation.</li>
          <li>Added Gemini (Google Generative Language API) as a fourth provider.</li>
          <li>Added an optional backup Ollama server URL with automatic failover, so a private home-LAN address can stay private while traffic transparently routes via VPN/Tailscale when out-of-network.</li>
          <li>Windows builds now bundle the VC++ runtime DLLs so horizon.exe launches without a separate Redistributable install.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
